本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
我刚才做了个噩梦
I just had a horrible dream
梦到吉迪恩偷走了神秘小屋的地契  把我们赶出来
that Gideon stole the deed to the Mystery Shack and kicked us out
我们不得不搬到苏斯的奶奶家里住
and we all had to move in with Soos's grandma.
这不是梦  伙计
That was no dream, dude.
嘘  拜托
Shh! Por Favovor.
呃  抱歉  奶奶
Uh, sorry abuelita.
噢  苏斯  你奶奶真可爱
Oh! Soos, your grandma is so adorable!
她的皮肤软得像老太太一样
And her skin is old lady soft.
梅宝  别怪里怪气的  新闻终于播了
Mabel, quit bebeing creepy! The news is finally on!
让重力泉为之哗然的事件
In a move that has all of Gravity Falls buzzing,
儿童通灵师吉迪恩・格里弗
child psychic Gideon Gleeful
突然取得了神秘小屋的所有权
has taken surprise ownership of the Mystery Shack,
该小屋此前属于本地骗子斯坦福・派恩斯
previously belonging to area shyster Stanford Pines.
这张照片选得有失公允
That picture's taken out of context.
现在你拥有了小屋
Now that you have the shack,
你打算具体用它来做什么呢
What exactly are you planning to do with it?
我今天有件重要的事情要宣布
I have a big announcement to make today,
我热忱地邀请
And I'd like to cordially invite
全重力泉镇的善良居民来我这做客
all the good people of Gravity Falls to join me.
只要戴上吉迪恩胸章就能免费加入
Free admission to everyone who wears their Gideon pins!
胸章上是我的脸哦
It's my face!
我实在不能相信吉迪恩打败了我们
I just can't believe Gideon beat us!
一般情况下我都可以挽救局面
Normally I'm able to save the day.
都是我的错
This is all my fault.
别担心  迪普
Don't worry, Dipper.
貌似要轮到梅宝成为全家的英雄了
Looks like Mabel's gonna have to be the hero of the family now!
我会使用我的爪钩打败吉迪恩
I'll defeat Gideon with my grappling hook!
梅宝  恕我直说  你的爪钩一次都没有帮上过忙
Mabel, no offense, but that grappling hook has literally never helped us once.
哦  真的吗  抓取果冻
Oh, yeah? Jelly grab!
我要用吸尘器清理墙壁
I vacuum the walls now.
你们失去了小屋  但是往好处想想  伙计
So you lost the shack. Look on the bright side, dudes.
现在你们可以和我住在一起了
Now you get to live here with me.
苏斯
Soos!
嘿  有人想玩赛车吗
Hey, anyone wanna play racecars?
没电了  但是我们可以假装有电来玩
They're out of batteries but we can make pretend.
如果我吃掉它是不是就刷新了我的下限
Would it be a new low if I ate that?
开玩笑啦  我绝对会吃掉它的
I'm just kidding. I'm totally eating it.
我们一定要把小屋夺回来
We've gotta get the shack back.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
CC录制： ufohaman  Qin Cong
时间轴： WaitinZ
■
翻译： wesyman  moonywen  Ally Bo
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  第一季第二十集
Gravity Falls  S01E20  Gideon Rises
神秘小屋关张大吉
重力泉居民们  你们好
Hello, Gravity Falls!
吉迪恩最灵了
Gideon is the psychic-est!
他猜到了我的咖啡煎蛋卷的秘密配方
He guessed the secret ingredient to my coffee omelet!
不懂他怎么知道我有块吓人的胎记的
Somehow he knew about my horrifying secret birthmark.
我真是太爱这个儿童通灵师了
I love that child psychic so much!
你要勒死我了
You're choking me!
奶奶  是你吗
Grandma, is that you?
我们进来了
We're in.
我只想说  不懂我们要来这里干嘛
Just wanna say, don't know what we're doing here,
但我真太喜欢这假胡子了
But I am loving these fake moustaches!
有人问的话  就说我不是苏斯
If anyone asks, I'm not Soos.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen!
今天我很高兴地宣布我对前神秘小屋的改造计划
Today I am delighted to announce my new plans for the former mystery shack.
我向你们呈现  吉迪恩乐园
I give you Gideonland!
什么  伙计
What?!! Dude!
我们要把这个肮脏的老屋
We're gonna turn this dirty old shack
改造成三平方英里的吉迪恩乐园
into three square miles of Gideon-tertainment!
并且  介绍我们的新吉祥物
And, introducing our new mascot,
小小吉迪恩
Li'l Gideon junior!
嘭  他是头小猪
Boom! He's a pig!
摇摇  你这禽兽
Waddles! You monster!
好吧  受够了
All right, that's it!
大伙  听好了  吉迪恩是个骗子
Listen up, people! Gideon's a fraud!
这熊孩子闯进我家  偷走了我的财产
This kid broke in and stole my property!
-逮捕他  警官  -对
- Arrest him, officers! - Yeah!
这是何等的指控啊
Such accusations!
派恩斯先生  我记得你是把财产赠送给我了
Mr. Pines, I recall you gave the property to me.
你看  地契就在这里呢
Look, here's the deed right here!
好吧  我只要看到这个证据就够了
Well, that's all the proof I need to see.
我爱你  小吉迪恩  给他们唱首好玩的歌吧
I love you, Li'l Gideon! Sing them funny songs!
离开我的地产  老头
Now get off my property, old man.
我让你见识下谁是老头
I'll show you who's the old ma--
我的助听器
Ow! Aah! My hearing aid! Aah!
朋友们  感谢你们参观吉迪恩乐园
Thanks for visiting Gideonland, friends!
别再回来了  我一点都不在乎你们
Don't come back. I don't care for y'all.
别担心  伙计们  我们会想到办法夺回小屋的
Don't worry, guys, we'll get the shack back somehow.
我们最好可以
We better.
温蒂
Wendy!
如果我不能在小屋工作的话
If I can't work at the shack,
我爸爸就要强迫我去表亲的伐木场工作了
My dad's gonna force me to work upstate at my cousin's logging camp.
什么  你要离开镇子吗  但是我们这里需要你
What? You're leaving town? But we need you here!
对  尤其是迪普  因为他超级喜欢
Yeah, especially dipper, because of his giant crush on...
你  桉树
You. Calyptus trees!
这孩子可喜欢桉树了
The kids loves eucalyptus trees.
我瞒过去了
Saved it!
噢  老天  伙计们  别看
Oh, man, guys, don't look now.
跟我和好吧  温蒂
Take me back, Wendy!
我的胳膊太瘦了  没法一直举着这台音响
My arms are too skinny to keep holding this boom box forever!
-就当我没来过这里  -你收到我短信了吗
- I was never here. - Have you been getting my texts?
我还需要继续给你发短信吗  温蒂
Do I need to send you more texts? Wendy!
这样不行啊  我养不活这么多口人
This is not good. I cannot feed such a big family.
我们能去哪儿呢  迪普
Where will we stay, Dipper?
我该把这些毛衣放在哪儿
Where will I put all my sweaters?
斯坦会和爸爸妈妈怎么说
And what's Stan gonna tell mom and dad?
派恩斯先生会想到办法的  他从来都有办法
Ah, Mr. Pines will figure something out. He always does!
别担心  你儿子和女儿好好的呢
Don't worry. Your son and daughter are fine.
我们住在哪儿
Where are we staying?
呃  我把他们放到这家豪华的四星级酒店了
Uh, I put 'em up at this amazing 4-star hotel!
什么  当然了  我们有的是吃的东西
What? Uh, sure, we got... plenty to eat.
呃  放松  如果我认为自己照顾不了孩子们的话
Uh, relax. If I thought I couldn't take care of these kids,
我会马上送他们回家  嗯哈  你也是
I'd send 'em back right away. Uh-huh. You, too.
斯坦叔公  我们可以叫披萨吗
Grunkle Stan, can we order pizza?
滚回角落去
Back to your corner!
我一直都想问你  儿子
I've been meanin' to ask you, boy.
你难道不应该为吉迪恩乐园庆祝一下
Shouldn't you be celebratin' Gideonland
而不是整天埋头读那本书
instead of sticking your head in that there book all day?
父亲  我有没有告诉过你这本书的真面目
Father, have I ever told you the true nature of this book?
这是很多年前  某位杰出的佚名作家所写的
It was written many years ago by a brilliant unknown author
他发现的秘密太过强大  不能落在一个人手里
who learned secrets too powerful for one man.
他把日志藏到他认为没有人会找得到的地方
He hid his journals where he thought no one would ever find 'em.
因为他知道  如果把日志收集完整
Because he knew that if the journals were ever brought together,
就能打开一扇通向无法想象的力量之门
They would unleash a gateway to unimaginable power!
这本书中的密码和地图告诉我
Codes and maps have led me to believe
另外一本书就藏在这片地产底下的某个地方
The other book's buried somewhere on this very property.
我打算找到它
And I intend to find it.
所以你才想要神秘小屋
So that's why you wanted the Mystery Shack.
是的  父亲
That's right, father.
是时候开始搜索
It's time to begin the search...
另一本日志了
For the other journal!
前进  红车
Go, red car!
前进  另一辆红车
Go, other red car!
有电池的话会好玩得多
This would be a lot more fun with batteries.
孩子们  我们谈一下
Kids, we gotta talk.
我一直在想  我没法继续照顾你们了
Look, I've been thinking, and I can't take care of you anymore.
我现在没有房子  也没有工作
I don't have a house, or-- or a job.
计划就是  你们回家
The plan is you're going home.
大巴明天出发  车票给你们
Your bus leaves tomorrow. Here are your tickets.
但是  斯坦叔公  你不能放弃
But, Grunkle Stan, you can't give up.
是的  伙计  看看他们的表情吧
Yeah, dude. Look at these faces!
梅宝  变可爱些  你的暑假就靠它了
Be cuter, Mabel! Your summer depends on it!
我输了  知道吗
Look, I lost, okay?
你们最好是和你们父母待在一起
The best thing is for you to be with your parents.
我很抱歉  孩子们  吉迪恩赢了
I'm sorry, kids. Gideon won.
暑假结束了
Summer's over.
派恩斯先生  快回来  三思啊
Mr. Pines! Come back! Reconsider!
梅宝  我受够了
Mabel, that's enough!
如果斯坦不从吉迪恩手中夺回我们的家园的话
If Stan won't get our home back from Gideon,
那我们就自己来
Then we'll have to do it ourselves!
吉迪恩可能占得先机
Gideon may have the upper hand,
但我们有一样他没有的东西
But we have one thing he doesn't.
-一把爪钩  -我的日志
- A grappling hook! - The journal!
哦  是日志
Oh, the journal.
日志
Journal!
我们正在打造神奇
好吧  带我们离开重力泉的巴士
All right. The bus to take us out of Gravity Falls
日落的时候到
comes at sundown.
如果我们想要留在镇上
If we wanna stay in town,
得先通过这些守卫
we've gotta get past those guards,
翻过铁网
Make it through the fence,
然后让吉迪恩交出地契
And get Gideon to hand over that deed.
交给梅宝吧  我射
Leave that to Mabel! Wa-cha!
现在你承认爪钩是没用的了吧
Now will you admit the grappling hook is useless?
不承认
Nope!
好  看看我们能拿什么打败吉迪恩
Okay, what can we use to defeat Gideon.
我们瞧瞧  呕吐仙女
Let's see. Barf fairy?
-好耶  -不要
-Yeah! -Nope.
带表情的人脸白胡桃南瓜
Butternuts squash with a human face and emotions?
-好耶  -不行
- Yeah! - Nope..
哇哦  这是什么
Whoaoa! What's this?
我曾花了很长时间研究这一页
I've stared at this page for hours.
看起来好像是建造某种
It seems like a blueprint to build some kind
奇怪的未来超级武器的蓝图
of strange futuristic super weapon--
真无聊  要打败那些守卫
Boring! To defeat those guards,
我们需要一支军队
we need some kind of army.
等等  一支军队
Wait a minute. An army!
梅宝  就是这个  小矮人
Mabel, that's it! The gnomes!
呃
Uh...
我看这里应该就是它们的藏身地点
I think this is their hiding spot.
我想知道小矮人们到底在树林里面鼓捣什么
I wonder what gnomes do out here all alone in the forest.
这  这很正常
This...this is normal.
小矮人这样洗澡很正常  洗刷刷  洗刷刷
This is normal for gnomes. Scrub, scrub.
哎呀呀  看看是谁低三下四地回来了
Well, well, well! Look who came crawling back!
你休息一下  克里斯
Take five, Chris.
你们几个别停下来继续啊
You guys keep doin' what you're doin'.
那么改变主意要嫁给我了  是吗  梅宝
So, changed your mind about marrying me, did you, Mabel?
恶心  才没有  我们需要你们的帮忙
Ew! Hardly! We need your help.
还有说真的  真恶心
And seriously, ew!
想让我们帮忙
You want our help?
在你在圣坛上抛弃我之后  想都别想
After you left me at the altar? No dice!
要是我们能帮你们找一位新女王呢
Well, what if we were able to get you a new queen?
一位比我更漂亮的女王
One even more beautiful than me!
她叫吉迪恩  拥有一头靓丽的白发
Her name's Gideon and she has lovely white hair.
哇哦  熟女诱惑是吧
Whoa! Mature woman, huh?
嘿  史麦布莱克  把我的古龙香水拿过来
Hey, Shmebulock, get my cologne!
史麦布莱克
Shmebulock!
你就会说“史麦布莱克”这几个字吗
Is "Shmebulock" all you can say?
史麦布莱克
Shmebulock.
成交
It's a deal!
服务员  我要一杯你们这里劲力最大
Waiter, give me a glass of the strongest,
过期最久的苹果汁
most expired apple cider you've got.
保证送到  派恩斯先生
Sure thing, Mr. Pines.
苏斯  你在这里干什么
Soos? What are you doing here?
自从神秘小屋关门之后
Since the Mystery Shack shut down,
我就得做好几份兼职
I've had to take a bunch of part-time jobs.
掘墓人  汽车司机  超赞的厨师
Grave digger, bus driver, really awesome cook.
对了  厨房里面应该
Hey, is the kitchen supposed to
生这么大的火吗
have that much fire in it?
苏斯  你是一个好心的大男孩
You're a good man-child, Soos,
但现在情况可不妙
But it's not looking good.
镇子里的人都喜欢吉迪恩而讨厌我
This whole town loves Gideon and hates me.
要是他们知道吉迪恩有多邪恶就好了
If only they knew how evil he really was.
有我在这儿呢  伙计
Hey, I'm here for you, dude.
你的整个下半身都着火了
The entire lower half of your body is on fire.
嘘  别打扰我们的宝贵时光
Shh. We're having a moment.
日志  你在哪里
Where are you, journal?
到底在哪里
Where are you?
孩子  我不想打断你  但是你有几位客人
Boy, I hate to interrupt you, but you have some guests.
什么
What?
把神秘小屋的地契还给我们  吉迪恩  否则
Give us the deed to the shack, Gideon! Or else!
我该问一句  否则就怎么样吗
Am I supposed to say, "Or else what?"
你是该这么问  动手
Yes, you are supposed to say that! Now!
你已经被一支坚不可摧的小矮人军队包围了
You're surrounded by an unstoppable gnome army.
现在把地契还给我们  滚出我们的地方
Now give us back our deed and get off our property!
结婚典礼快点开始吧
And let the marriage ceremony begin!
那好吧  我想这份地契应该属于
Very well. I suppose this deed belongs to--
哈  没想到啊  这招对小矮人也管用
Ha! What do you know? Works on gnomes, too.
别吹了  要我们做什么都行
Stop! We'll do anything!
我们该怎么服侍您  主人
How can we serve you, your majesty?
您是我们见过最美丽的女孩
The most beautiful girl we've ever seen!
我不是女孩
I am not a girl!
真的吗  但是你的皮肤如此柔软
Really? But your skin is so soft.
你抹了保湿霜还是
You moisturize or...
干掉他们
Subdue them!
孩子们  我得承认
I have to admit, kids,
你们的想象力给我留下了很深的印象
I am impressed by your creativity.
-你们怎么会  -放手
- How did you ever? - Let go!
噢  不
Oh, no!
不是吧  会是这个吗  是吗
No! Could it be? Is it?
当然是了
Of course!
这就解释得通了
It all makes sense!
我唯一没想到要找的地方
The one place I'd never think to look.
原来一直在你这里
You had it the whole time!
而我竟然真的把你当成一个威胁
And to think I actually considered you a threat!
不要  还给我
No! Give it back!
你的每一次成功都因为你有这本珍贵的书
Every victory you had was because of your precious book!
-还给我否则我就  -你就怎样啊 小屁孩
- Give it back or I'll-- - Or you'll what, boy?
你就怎样啊  说啊  说啊
You'll what? Huh? Huh?
一没肌肉二没脑子
No muscles, no brains.
面对现实吧  没这本书你什么都不是
Face it. You're nothing without this!
各位  永别了
Bye-bye forever, y'all.
不
No!
下次脏活你们自己做
Next time, do your own dirty work!
过来吧  孩子们
Come on, boys!
好吧  就这样了
Well, that's it.
我猜大巴马上就来了
Guess the bus should be here soon.
什么  迪普  别放弃啊
What? Dipper, don't give up!
你总能想出好主意的
You always have a plan!
不  好主意都是日志里面的
No, the journal always has the plan!
你想想吧  梅宝  吉迪恩说的没错
Think about it, Mabel. Gideon was right.
我做的所有勇敢或很酷的事情
The only courageous or cool things I've ever done
都是因为有那本日志
have been because of that journal.
没有它  我根本帮不了你或斯坦  或者任何人
Without it, I can't help you or Stan or anyone.
我们肯定能做点什么的
There's gotta be something we can do.
我们能做什么
What can we do?
离开重力泉的52路汽车  乘客请上车
Bus fifty-two departing Gravity Falls. All aboard.
对不起  孩子们  这样也好
Sorry, kids. It's for the best.
真不敢相信会是这样
Can't believe this is happening.
即将离开重力泉
到手了  终于到手了
I've got it! I've finally got it!
出去
Get out!
终于是我的了
It's finally mine!
终于啊  我得到了日志的第
At last, I have journal number...
三号
Three?
一共有三本日志
There are three of 'em?
那一号日志到哪里去了
But where is journal number one?
我必须集齐三本日志才能释放力量
I must have all three for the power to be unlocked!
但要在哪里才能找到  迪普  他肯定知道在哪里
But where could I-- Dipper! He must know where it is!
他把第三本给了我  自己留了第一本
He gave me the third one and kept the first for himself!
我不能让他离开重力泉
I can't let him leave Gravity Falls!
上面的  准备好了吗
You there! Is it ready?
只有一个办法才能知道
Only one way to find out!
我对那孩子感觉很不错
I got a good feelin' about that kid!
斯坦  接受吧  陷入人生低谷
Well, Stan, this is it. Rock bottom.
没有朋友  没有家人
No friends, no family,
困在这里收看莫名其妙的电视购物广告
Stuck watching infomercials for whatever that is.
你厌倦了经常阻挡你车道的
Are you sick of piles of owls
成堆的猫头鹰了吗
constantly blocking your driveway?
那么你需要一把猫头鹰铲
Well, then you've gotta get owl trowel!
你是怎么做到的  孩子
How did you do it, kid?
为什么你总能先人一步
Why are you always one step ahead?
也许他真的可以通灵
Maybe he really is psychic after--
啊  我的助听器
Aah! My hearing aid!
怎么老这样
What keeps causing that?
等会儿  我想到了
Wait a minute. That's it!
我知道吉迪恩的弱点在哪了
I know Gideon's weakness!
派恩斯先生要不要来一杯
Would Mr. Pines like a--
我要用吸尘器打扫我的脸
I go vacuum my face.
嘿  迪普  想玩汽车座位寻宝游戏吗
Hey, Dipper. Wanna play bus seat treasure hunt?
我没心思
I'm not in the mood.
拜托嘛
Oh, come on.
我们有加拿大硬币
We got Canadian coin,
罗纳德・里根脑袋形状的口香糖
Gum that's shaped like Ronald Reagan's head.
（注：美国前总统）
喔  各种液体的污渍哦
Ooh! Miscellaneous fluid stain.
-巨型机器人  -对  还有巨型机器人  等下  啥
- Giant robot! - Yeah, giant robot. Wait. What?
-你看  -停车  你们给我停车
- Look! - Halt! I command you to halt!
司机先生  有个巨型吉迪恩机器人追上来了
Mr. Bus driver! There's a giant Gideonbot coming towards us!
-嗨  伙计们  -苏斯
- Ho hey, dudes! - Soos!
别担心  我至少也当了四十分钟的兼职巴士司机
Don't worry, guys. I've been a part-time bus driver for at least 40 minutes.
这里面肯定有一个是离合器
One of these things is probably a clutch.
抓紧啦  孩子们
Hang on, dudes!
-苏斯  小心  -啊
- Soos! Look out! - Aah!
他已经赢了  他还抓我们干什么啊
He already won! What does he want from us?
我已经看到你们了
I got you in my sights!
苏斯  前面是悬崖
Soos! Cliff!
好吧  哪个更符合现在的情况
Okay, what's closest to our present situation?
“引擎里有浣熊”还是“不肯下车的愤怒老爷爷”
"Raccoon in the engine" or "Angry grandparent won't leave bus"?
大概  大概是第二个吧
Probably-- probably the second one.
说  一号日志在哪里
Tell me! Where is journal number one?
一号日志
Journal number one?
别给我耍小聪明  臭小子
Don't play games with me, boy!
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about!
你拿走了我唯一的日志
You took the only journal I ever had!
还有  你到底想要从这些日志中得到什么啊
What do you even want with these journals, anyway?
放开她
Let go of her!
哈哈哈  事到如今你还觉得自己是个英雄么
Ha ha ha! You still think you're some kind of hero?
一旦我找到最后一本日志  这个小镇就是我的了
Once I find the final journal, I'll rule this town!
你会成为我的王后
With you as my queen!
迪普  救救我  救命啊
Dipper, help me! Help!
面对现实吧  小子  没了那本日志你什么都不是
Face it, kid. You're nothing without that journal.
你要怎么反抗啊
How you gonna fight back?
一没肌肉二没脑子
No muscles, no brains.
你要怎么做  啊  你要怎么做
What are you gonna do? Huh? What are you gonna do?
放开我姐姐
Let go of my sister!
绝不  这次我终于赢了
Never! I finally won this time!
一边去  放开我
Aah! Aah! Get off! Let go of me!
什么
Huh?
在里面小心点
Careful in there!
孩子们  不
Dudes! No!
爪钩万岁
Grappling hook!
我就说它会派上用场吧
Told you it would come in handy.
梅宝  这真是太厉害了
Mabel, that was amazing!
没有你击败那个机器人的时候厉害
Not as amazing as you defeating that robot!
嘿  我的日志
Hey, my journal!
-哦  在那边  -刚才爆炸的是这个东西么
- Oh, there it is! - Is this the thing that exploded?
发生什么了  那是什么啊
What's going on? What is that?
在这儿
It's over here.
吉迪恩
Gideon!
上帝啊  这里到底发生了什么
Oh, good heavens! What on earth happened here?
是派恩斯两姐弟  他们想攻击我
It was the Pines twins. They tried to attack me
还用炸药毁了我的雕像
and blew up my statue with dynamite!
抓住他们
Arrest 'em!
什么  警官们  他在撒谎
What? Officers, he's lying!
抱歉  孩子们  但是我们信任吉迪恩
Sorry, kids, but we trust Gideon,
只有发生不折不扣的奇迹才可能改变我们的
And nothing short of a miracle could ever change our--
等一下  等一下  都住手  我有话说
Wait! Wait! Stop everything! I've got something to say!
-怎么又是他啊  -等一等  听着
- Not this guy again. - Just wait! Look!
你们都觉得吉迪恩超级完美超级诚实
You guys all think Gideon is so perfect and honest.
“哦  我永远都不会撒谎  我可是吉迪恩啊”
"Oh, I could never tell a lie! I'm Gideon!"
他比你诚实多了
He's more honest than you!
对啊  而且他还会通灵
Yeah! And he's psychic too!
那这个算不算通灵  好好看看
How's this for psychic? Bam! Take a good look!
等一下啊  那是我么
Wait a minute! Is that me?
我的咖啡蛋饼的秘密配方是咖啡
The secret ingredient to my coffee omelet is coffee!
还有我
And me!
我可以明确地说那个胎记确实很恶心
I can verify that that birthmark is indeed disgusting.
哦耶
Hooray!
那是我
That's me!
对的  这些胸针都是隐藏摄像机
That's right! These pins are hidden cameras!
令我的助听器一直发出反馈杂音
And my hearing aid was picking up the feedback!
现在谁是骗子呢
Who's the fraud now?
吉迪恩  我们这么相信你
Gideon, we gave you our trust.
你竟然欺骗我们
You lied to us!
请听我说  我  事实不是看起来的那样
Please, I-- it's not what it looks like.
你们要对我怎么样
What are you gonna do with me?
泰勒
Tyler?
抓住他
Get him.
小吉迪恩  你现在被逮捕了
Li'l Gideon, you are under arrest...
因为阴谋  欺诈  和伤透了我们的心的罪名
For conspiracy, fraud, and breaking our hearts.
杜兰德  拿出微型手铐
Durland, the tiny handcuffs.
什么  不
Wha-- no!
还有一件事
Just one more thing.
放开我
Let go of me! Ow! Ow! Ow!
我想这个是属于我的
I believe this belongs to me.
不  不  别弄乱我的头发
No! No! Watch the hair!
你不能这么对我  你们这群乌合之众
You can't do this to me! Y'all are sheep!
你们需要我  我会回来的
You need me! I'll be back!
我的律师会通知你们消息的
You'll hear from my lawyers!
这就是今天的新闻
There you have it.
本地英雄斯坦福・派恩斯刚刚揭露了
Local hero Stanford Pines has just exposed
小吉迪恩这个骗子的真实身份
Li'l Gideon as a fraud.
斯坦福  有什么想对乡亲们说的吗
Anything you have to say to the town, Stanford?
神秘小屋回来啦  亲们
The Mystery Shack is back, baby!
谢谢  谢谢
Oh, thank you, thank you!
小吉迪恩蹲大牢
嘿  斯坦叔公
Hey, Grunkle Stan!
你们这两个小屁孩安顿得还好么
Uh, you kiddos settling back in okay?
很好  房间里所有我最喜欢的霉点
Yep! All of my favorite moldy spots
都还在天花板上呢
On the ceiling are still there!
甚至是你哦  戴里尔
Even you, Daryl!
斯坦叔公  我和梅宝商量过了
Hey, Grunkle Stan, me and Mabel have been talking,
有些事情我们觉得还是应该告诉你
And I think there's something we should finally tell you.
这本日志是我在森林里找到的
This is a journal I found in the woods.
里面写满了发生在重力泉不可思议的事情
It talks about all the crazy stuff that goes on in Gravity Falls.
吉迪恩为了找它差点毁了整个镇子
Gideon nearly destroyed the whole town trying to find it.
我不知道它代表着什么  也不知道是谁写的
I don't know what it means, or who wrote it,
但是在我们经历了这么多之后
But after all we've been through,
也许你最终还是应该知道这件事
Maybe you should finally know about it.
很高兴你能给我看这本日记  迪普
I'm glad you showed me this, Dipper.
我终于知道你那些胡思乱想是从哪儿来的了
Now I know where you've been getting it all from!
幽灵啦  怪兽啦
Spookums and monsters.
都是这本怪异的书在
This kooky book has been
往你的脑子里灌输疯狂的阴谋论
filling your head with crazy conspiracies!
但是它们都是真的啊
But it's all real!
为了你自己好  不要再读这些胡诌的故事了
You gotta quit readin' this fantasy nonsense for your own good.
不过其中有些东西倒是可以引起很大的轰动
Although some of these would make great attractions!
（带表情的人脸白胡桃南瓜）
我可想不出这些玩意儿  借我一用啦
Can't come up with this stuff! Mind if I borrow this?
等一下  不  斯坦叔公
Wait! No! Grunkle Stan!
“魔法书” 真是荒谬
"Magic book." Ridiculous!
-斯坦  我需要它  -迪普  你不需要那本书
- Stan, I need it! - Dipper, you don't need that book!
你还不明白吗
Don't you see?
你一个人击败了巨型机器人
On your own you defeated a giant robot
全凭你自己的力量
with nothing but your bare hands!
不管有没有那本书  你都是个英雄
You're a hero whether you've got that journal or not!
谢谢  梅宝
Whoa. Thanks, Mabel.
但我还是想把它要回来
I still want it back though.
我相信你以后会拿回来的
I'm sure you'll get it back.
像斯坦那样的无聊老男人要那本书做什么
What would a boring old man like Stan want with that book anyway?
被苏斯整了吧
Soos'ed!
这么多年过去了
After all these years.
我总算是集齐了所有的日志
Finally, I have them all.
它启动了
It's working!
好戏上演啦
Here we go.
本季完结